Lucy Toman

Full stack web developer Berlin, Germany

****** +49(0)157 5256 2484

https://lucysco.de

@ lucy@toman.me.uk

https://github.com/lucywho

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucytoman

Personal Profile

I am a full stack web developer with a background in project management. I have 15 years' experience working in multidisciplinary teams solving complex problems with qualitative and quantitative data

Skills

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express, Handlebars, Vue, React, Redux, Socket.io, PostgreSQL, MySQL, AWS, Git, Agile

Education

Full stack web development bootcamp

SPICED Academy, Berlin Intensive, hands-on, projectbased training course

Bachelor of Education (Hons) Secondary Science

Sheffield Hallam University, UK

Languages

English (native)
German (intermediate)
French (basic)

Full Stack projects

Prepositioner

React.js, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL

Practice German Prepositions
Features: ten random questions, unlimited retries, show correct answer, score keeping and positive feedback.

Qira's Folk

React.js, Node.js, Express Socket.io, AWS SES & S3, PostgreSQL

A social network for the worst RPG group ever!
Features: registration, login and password reset.
Edit personal profile and picture, make and accept friend requests. Chat room.

Imaginary Realities

Vue.js, Node.js, Express, AWS S3, PostgreSQL

An imageboard for photos from the Hubble telescope

Features: Single page application for user image uploads, thumbnail and large image views, user comments on individual images.

Who For All!

Handlebars, Node.js, Canvas, PostgreSQL

A petition to bring Doctor Who to the world!
Features: registration and login, signing using mouse, optional additional personal details, signature and personal details editing, view all other signatories or signatories by city.

Employment History

2018 - 2020 Freelance content and project manager

Various clients

Designed a content management system for an Apple-featured consumer app. Project managed a small team of software engineers to build the system and delivered training to the company

2014 – 2018 Career break: travelling and learning German

2012 – 2014 Senior Executive Officer, Department for Education

UK Government

Interventions Officer: used national statistical datasets to drive improvement in children's services. Worked with local leaders to agree targeted change plans, monitored progress and made regular reports to government ministers.

High-impact Projects Team: I was a founding member of a departmentwide team of project specialists, delivering "first-aid" and focussed support to help key projects deliver on time and to budget.

2000 – 2012 Higher Executive Officer, Department for Environment

UK Government

Project Officer: worked on a large number of legislation changes, often to tight regulatory deadlines. Liaised with specialist colleagues, wrote evidence-based business plans, risk and impact assessments. Lead on stakeholder communications programmes to secure buy-in for potentially controversial policy changes.

Development Manager: staff mentoring, coaching and performance reviews.

Other Skills, Training and Qualifications

Ongoing	Deutsche als Fremdsprache / German as a foreign language
2016	Bundesamt für Migration und Flüchtlinge Intergrationskurs
2016	telc Deutch-Test für Zuwanderer B1 Zertifikat
2006	UK Cabinet Office Certificate of Programme and Project Management
2006	UK Government Risk Management Certificate